<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Registry of Open Data on AWS</title>
    <link>https://registry.opendata.aws</link>
    <description>Recent datasets listed on the Registry of Open Data on AWS</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>opendata@amazon.com</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 14:27:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Sentinel-2</title>
      <link>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel-2</link>
      <guid>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel-2</guid>
      <description>The &lt;a href&#x3D;&quot;https://sentinel.esa.int/web/sentinel/missions/sentinel-2&quot;&gt;Sentinel-2 mission&lt;/a&gt; is
a land monitoring constellation of two satellites that provide high resolution
optical imagery and provide continuity for the current SPOT and Landsat missions.
The mission provides a global coverage of the Earth&amp;#39;s land surface every 5 days,
making the data of great use in on-going studies. L1C data are available from
June 2015 globally. L2A data are available from September 2016 over wider Europe
region and globally since January 2017. Test change</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentinel-3</title>
      <link>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel-3</link>
      <guid>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel-3</guid>
      <description>This data set consists of observations from the Sentinel-3 satellite of the European Commission’s Copernicus Earth Observation Programme. Sentinel-3 is a polar orbiting satellite that completes 14 orbits of the Earth a day. It carries the Ocean and Land Colour Instrument (OLCI) for medium resolution marine and terrestrial optical measurements, the Sea and Land Surface Termperature Radiometer (SLSTR), the SAR Radar Altimeter (SRAL), the MicroWave Radiometer (MWR) and the Precise Orbit Determination (POD) instruments. The satellite was launched in 2016 and entered routine operational phase in 2017. Data is available from July 2017 onwards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentinel-1 SLC dataset for South and Southeast Asia, Taiwan, Korea and Japan</title>
      <link>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel1-slc-seasia-pds</link>
      <guid>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel1-slc-seasia-pds</guid>
      <description>The S1 Single Look Complex (SLC) dataset contains Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) data in the C-Band wavelength. The SAR sensors are installed on a two-satellite (Sentinel-1A and Sentinel-1B) constellation orbiting the Earth with a combined revisit time of six days, operated by the European Space Agency. The S1 SLC data are a Level-1 product that collects radar amplitude and phase information in all-weather, day or night conditions, which is ideal for studying natural hazards and emergency response, land applications, oil spill monitoring, sea-ice conditions, and associated climate change effects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentinel-2 L2A 120m Mosaic</title>
      <link>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel-s2-l2a-mosaic-120</link>
      <guid>https://registry.opendata.aws/sentinel-s2-l2a-mosaic-120</guid>
      <description>Sentinel-2 L2A 120m mosaic is a derived product, which contains best pixel values for 10-daily periods, modelled by removing the cloudy pixels and then performing interpolation among remaining values. As there are some parts of the world, which have lengthy cloudy periods, clouds might be remaining in some parts. The actual modelling script is available &lt;a href&#x3D;&quot;https://sentinel-hub.github.io/custom-scripts/sentinel-2/interpolated_time_series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>